Finding Aid for the Frederick Caldecott Slee Collection of Manuscript Scores, 1890-1954
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Frederick Caldecott Slee Collection of Manuscript Scores, 1890-1954
Mus. Arc. 12.1
Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954
3 boxes (77 items)
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
The collection contains scores and parts of original compositions and arrangements by Frederick Slee. It also includes transcriptions of works by composers such as J.S. Bach, Mozart, and Haydn, as well as a lesson for recorder.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
Gift
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Biographical Note
Frederick Caldecott Slee (1870-1954) was a successful corporate lawyer in Buffalo, N.Y. While at Harvard pursuing his law degree, he also studied music theory, composition, and performance. He later furthered his music education by studying under Ernest Schelling and Walter Damrosch in New York City and Nadia Boulanger at the Sorbonne in Paris. An accomplished musician who played viola, violin, piano and cello, Slee formed a string quartet that performed locally in Buffalo. He composed more than three dozen works including several songs, works for string quartet and other chamber ensembles, a choral work, a work for solo organ, and an orchestral work.
Scope and Content Note
The Frederick Caldecott Slee Collection of Manuscript Scores, 1890-1954 contains 77 folders of bound and unbound paper manuscript scores and parts, with many including photostatic reproductions. It also contains transcriptions of works by Alexander von Fielitz, J.S. Bach, Mozart, and Haydn; and a lesson for recorder. There are 41 original works and arrangements, 5 transcriptions and 1 recorder lesson represented in the collection.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in two series: I. Original works and arrangements by Frederick Caldecott Slee; II. Transcriptions and recorder lesson
Container List
- Original works and arrangements by Frederick Caldecott Slee, 1890-1954, I; Items 1-71
  Arranged alphabetically by title of the composition.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Air and variations, string quartet Air and variations / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [1927?], 1 ms. score ([9] p.) + 4 ms. parts; 35 cm. (Box 1, Item 01)
    Score: holograph in pencil; parts: manuscript in ink with pencil emendations by composer. Title from caption on score. "Theme varie` (stringed quartet)"--original envelope. Parts marked "Last" in red pencil. Score is marked with a cut, an addition on insertion, and tacet markings; it is also marked with additional sketches on t.p. Major sections of the score are marked with the following tempo markings: Allegro -- Poco meno mosso -- Andante -- Allegro vivace -- Moderato (marked to be omitted) -- Tempo di valse -- Allegro scherzando -- Adagio molto. 2nd violin part contain changes on pasted inserts.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Air and variations, string quartet Air and variations / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [1927?], 4 ms. parts; 35 cm. (Box 1, Item 02)
    Holograph in ink with pencil emendations. Caption title. "Theme varie` (stringed quartet)"--original envelope. "Original"--enclosing piece of score paper. Major sections of the work are inconsistently marked with the following tempo markings: Allegro -- (Poco) meno mosso -- Allegretto -- Allegro -- Moderato -- Allegro scherzando -- Adagio molto. All parts contain changes on pasted inserts.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Air and variations, string quartet Air and variations / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [1927?], 4 ms. parts; 35 cm. (Box 1, Item 03)
    Holograph in ink and pencil. Title from caption of 1st violin part. "Theme varie` (stringed quartet)"--original envelope. The 2nd violin part contains a pencil sketch of an interior section of the work in full score format on its outer leaves. Major sections of the work are marked with the following tempo markings: Moderato -- Andante -- Allegro -- Allegro scherzando -- Adagio.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Air and variations, string quartet (Sketches) [Air and variations / Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [1927?], 1 ms. score ([6] p.); 20-37 cm. (Box 1, Item 04)
    Holograph (Pencil). Title from cataloger. Score varies from condensed to full format. Separated into three sheets. Page [1] of score is on verso of ms. score of one page of Slee's composition, Reminiscence, dated 1927.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Air varie´: for cello / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [193-?], 1 ms. score (6 p.) + 1 ms. part ([2] p.); 32 cm. (Box 1, Item 05)
    Holograph (Ink). For violoncello and piano. Cover title.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Air varie´: for cello / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. 1935., 1 ms. score (6 p.) + 1 ms. part ([2] p.); 32 cm. (Box 1, Item 06)
    Holograph (Ink). For violoncello and piano. Cover title. "Revised Nov. 10, 1935"--Cover.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Bagatelle, violin, piano Bagatelle / Caldecott. [between 1890 and 1954], 1 ms. score ([2] p.) + 1 ms. part ([1] p.); 35 cm. (Box 1, Item 07)
    Manuscript (Ink). For violin and piano. Caption title. "For Isabelle"--p. [1].
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Bravery / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [193-?], 1 ms. score ([2] p.); 32 cm. (Box 1, Item 08)
    Holograph in ink and pencil. For voice and piano. Caption title. Setting of Robert Frost's poem, Bravado, from the collection, New Hampshire, 1923. Contains changes marked on original score paper and on pasted inserts. Contains musical sketches on front and back covers. "Orig to be changed"--Cover. "Bravery. Bravery Bosh!"--Back cover.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Bravery / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [193-?], 1 ms. score ([2] p.); 32 cm. + 1 ms. part ([2] p.); 15 x 23 cm. (Box 1, Item 09)
    Holograph (Ink). For voice and piano. Caption title. Setting of Robert Frost's poem, Bravado, from the collection, New Hampshire, 1923. Two photostatic copies of score inserted.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Chorale, string quartet Chorale / Caldecott. 1944., 1 ms. score ([2] p.); 32 cm. + 4 ms. parts; 31 cm. (Box 1, Item 10)
    Holograph in ink and pencil. For string quartet. Caption title. Score marked "Jan 1939" in the caption and "Apr 1944" in the colophon. Contains revisions in pencil and ink applied directly to manuscript.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Cocoon / [music by Frederick Caldecott Slee; text by] Kathleen Millay. [193-?], 1 ms. score ([2] p.); 31 cm. + 1 ms. part (1 leaf); 21 x 23 cm. (Box 1, Item 11)
    Holograph in ink and pencil. For voice and piano. Caption title. Setting of Kathleen Millay's poem, Cocoon, from the collection, The Hermit Thrush, 1929. Vocal part contains sketches crossed out on back of leaf.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Cocoon / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [193-?], 1 ms. score ([2] p.); 31 cm. (Box 1, Item 12)
    Holograph (Ink). For voice and piano. Caption title. Setting of Millay's poem, Cocoon, from the collection, The Hermit Thrush, 1929. Two photostatic copies inserted.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Dialogue: poem from the Russian; music adapted for soprano, mezzo soprano, violin and viola, from Grieg's orchestral version of a folk-song / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1890 and 1954], 1 ms. score (5 p.); 35 cm. + 4 ms. parts; 21-35 cm. (Box 1, Item 13)
    Holograph in ink and pencil. Complete text in English on typescript piece of paper attached to verso of mezzo part. "Original Title "Glamour," song of the Caucasian mountaineers, translated through the Russian from the original Lesghian by Geo. Kennan."--Mezzo soprano part verso. "Final viola"--Viola part cover. All parts contain changes on pasted inserts. Violin and viola parts contain musical sketches crossed out on back covers; soprano part contains musical sketches crossed out on front and back covers.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Dialogue: poem from the Russian; music adapted for soprano, mezzo soprano, violin and viola, from Grieg's orchestral version of a folk-song / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1890 and 1954], 1 ms. score ([5] p.); 35 cm. + 2 ms. parts; 31 cm. (Box 1, Item 14)
    Holograph in ink and pencil. Score and parts contain changes on pasted inserts. Includes violin and viola parts only. Viola part contains another version of the last page for the part. Score contains 2 versions of p. [4]; the later version attached on top of the original.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Eclogue / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1890 and 1954], 2 ms. scores ([3] p.); 35 cm. + 2 ms. parts ([1] leaf); 32 cm. (Box 1, Item 15)
    Holograph in ink and pencil. For violin and piano. Caption title.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Facets: various aspects of the same theme / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1890 and 1954], 1 ms. score (7 p.); 35 cm. (Box 1, Item 16)
    Holograph in ink and pencil. For piano trio. Caption title. Contains changes on pasted inserts. The original ink title in the caption, Fantasia, is crossed out in pencil.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Facets: trio for piano, violin and cello / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1890 and 1954], 1 ms. score ([7] p.); 33 cm. + 2 ms. parts; 31 cm. (Box 1, Item 17)
    Holograph in ink and pencil. Cover title. Two photostatic copies of the score and parts inserted. Cello part contains changes on pasted inserts. "Facettes: Aspects varie´s d'une melodie-Dictionnaire Musical"--Caption.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Fantasia, violin Fantasia for violin alone / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1890 and 1954], [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 1, Item 18)
    Holograph in ink and pencil.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Fête galante. English & French Fe^te galante = Garden party / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1890 and 1954], 1 ms. score ([2] p.); 31 cm. (Box 1, Item 19)
    Holograph in ink and pencil. Setting of Paul Verlaine's Mandoline from his Fête galante. "English text and setting by Cal de Cott"--p. [1] caption, first photostatic copy. Includes 2 photostatic copies of the score; all 3 scores contain changes on ms. inserts.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Gavotte, string quartet Gavotte / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1890 and 1954], 1 ms. score ([3] p.); 35 cm. + 4 ms. parts; 32 cm. (Box 1, Item 20)
    Score: holograph in pencil; parts: manuscript in ink with pencil emendations by composer.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Gavotte, string quartet (Sketch) Gavotte / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1890 and 1954], 1 ms. score ([4] p.); 31 cm. (Box 1, Item 21)
    Holograph (Pencil). Title supplied by cataloger. Complete sketch with 1st violin on its own stave and the remainder in piano score format.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Golden myth / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1940 and 1954], 1 ms. score ([3] p.); 31 cm. (Box 1, Item 22)
    Holograph (Ink). Text by Eugene Ginsberg. Contains a revision on a pasted insert. Includes three photostatic copies of score with brown paper covers bound separately.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Gulf stream / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1890 and 1954], 1 ms. score ([2] p.); 31 cm. (Box 1, Item 23)
    Holograph in ink and pencil. Text by Walter W. Stephen. Cover includes words of song typewritten as text on a pasted insert. Score contains revisions in pencil and on a pasted insert. Two photostatic copies of score inserted.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Idylls Five idylls: for piano / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1890 and 1954], [7] p. of ms. music; 32 cm. (Box 1, Item 24)
    Holograph in ink and pencil. Score contains revisions in pencil and on a pasted insert in ink. Includes typewritten texts for all five works on inserts located at the beginning of each work. Loose insert containing the titles of the collection and the individual works clipped to the cover.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Idylls Five idylls: for piano / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1890 and 1954], [7] p. of ms. music; 32 cm. (Box 1, Item 25)
    Holograph in ink and pencil. Contains revisions applied directly on score and on pasted inserts. Contains loose inserts. Includes texts on inserts either handwritten in ink (1st-4th works) or typewritten (5th work) that are located at the beginning of each work. "These exercises in interpretation are printed without indication of tempo and nuances. The pupil will adopt such as seem to him appropriate to the sentiment of the verses. (This draft carries the marks of expression which are to be omitted if the suggestion above is adopted)"--Cover.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Last night I stole away alone / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [1943], 1 ms. score ([4] p.); 35 cm. (Box 2, Item 26)
    Holograph in ink and pencil. Caption title. Text by Celia Thaxter. "Revised Aug 1943"--Cover. Contains inserts and revisions in pencil and ink. Loose inserts stored in separate envelope.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Last night I stole away alone / [text by] Celia Thaxter; [music by Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1900 and 1943], 1 ms. score ([4] p.) + 1 ms. part ([2] p.); 35 cm. (Box 2, Item 27)
    Holograph in ink and pencil. Text by Celia Thaxter. "1 copy[,] 1 voice part"--Cover. Contains revisions in pencil and ink directly on manuscript and on inserts.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Last night I stole away alone; arr. Last night I stole away alone: for voice and orchestra / [text by] (Celia Thaxter); setting by Slee; orchestration by Frederick W. Krafft. [between 1900 and 1943], 1 ms. score ([12] p.); 27 x 35 cm. + 23 ms. parts; 31 cm. (Box 2, Item 28)
    Ms. in ink with pencil emendations by the composer. Orig. for voice and piano. Cover title. Score and parts contain tempo, dynamic, bowing and other markings in blue pencil.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Last night I stole away alone / text by Celia Thaxter; music by Fred'k Caldecott Slee. [between 1900 and 1943], 1 ms. score ([5] p.); 35 cm. (Box 2, Item 29)
    Holograph in ink with pencil emendations. Caption title.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Last night I stole away alone / text by Celia Thaxter; music by Fred'k Caldecott Slee. [between 1900 and 1943], 1 ms. score ([5] p.); 36 cm. (Box 2, Item 30)
    Ms. (Ink). Caption title.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Lay of the fascinating midget / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [1898], [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 2, Item 31)
    Holograph in ink and pencil. Caption title. Author of text unknown. "Her Beau August [3], 1898"--Caption. Text set above piano part; no separate vocal line.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Litany / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1890 and 1954], 1 ms. score ([2] p.); 31 cm. (Box 2, Item 32)
    Holograph (Ink). Song for voice and piano. Caption title. Setting of Robert Cameron Rogers's poem, The Rosary. Two photostatic copies of score inserted.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Love ye the Lord: (Psalm XXXI) / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1940 and 1947], 1 ms. score ([4] p.); 35 cm. + 4 ms. parts; 31 cm. (Box 2, Item 33)
    Score: holograph in ink and pencil; parts: holograph (Ink). For SATB and organ. Cover title. Text derived from Psalm 31 of The Bible. "1948"--Colophon. "To be revised to 1948"--Cover, alto part. Score and parts contain revisions on pasted inserts. Includes 5 photostatic copies of the score. Each copy contains numerous ms. inserts to make them agree with the original.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Madrigal, voices (2) Madrigal for two voices / [text by] Austin Dobson; [music by Frederick Caldecott Slee]. 1941., 1 ms. score ([2] p.); 31 cm. (Box 2, Item 34)
    Holograph in ink and pencil. Duet for unaccompanied voices (bass-baritone and mezzo-soprano). Caption title. Additional title in caption, Phillis, crossed out in pencil. "Sept. 1941"--Colophon. Contains revisions in pencil.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Madrigal, voices (2) Madrigal for two voices / [text by] Austin Dobson; [music by Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [1941?], 2 ms. scores ([2] p. each); 31 cm. (Box 2, Item 35)
    Holograph in ink and pencil. Duet for unaccompanied voices (bass-baritone and mezzo-soprano). Caption title. Contains revisions in pencil.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Metaphor / [text] after Shakespeare; [music by Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [1944], 2 ms. scores ([2] p. each); 31 cm. (Box 2, Item 36)
    Holograph in ink and pencil. Text from Shakespeare's Love's labour's lost: Spring (When daisies pied and violets blue), 2nd verse. "Aug. 1944"--Cover of both copies, colophon of one copy; "Aug. 1942"--colophon, other copy. Contains revisions in pencil applied directly to manuscript and in ink on pasted inserts.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Monody / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1934 and 1954], 1 ms. score ([2] p.); 31 cm. (Box 2, Item 37)
    Holograph in ink and pencil. Caption title. Text by Jose´ Garci´a Villa (stated as Jose´ Villa Garci´a in colophon). Contains words of the song typewritten as text on a pasted insert. Contains revisions in pencil applied directly to manuscript and in ink on pasted inserts.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Monody / Cal de Cott. [between 1934 and 1954], 4 scores ([2] p.); 31 cm. + 3 parts (1 leaf); 28 cm. (Box 2, Item 38)
    Caption title. Text by Jose´ Garci´a Villa (stated as Jose´ Villa Garci´a on scores). "Monody for baryton"--Cover, one copy of score. All copies of the score contain words of the song typewritten as text on a pasted ms. insert. All parts contain revisions on ms. inserts. All parts contain words of song typewritten as text at the end of the music.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Music, tenor, string quartet Music for tenor voice and strings / poem by Eichendorff; [music by Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1890 and 1954], 1 ms. score ([7] p.); 35 cm. (Box 2, Item 39)
    Holograph in ink and pencil. Cover title. "Thine image pure and smiling, song, tenor & string quartet"--Enclosing wrapper. "First draft"--Cover. Incomplete ink score of first 9 measures inserted. Contains revisions in pencil applied directly to manuscript and in pencil and ink on pasted inserts. Loose inserts enclosed in envelope.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Music, tenor, string quartet. English & German Dein Bildniss wunderselig: for tenor voice, 2 vln, viola, cello / of a poem by Eichendorff; [music by Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1890 and 1954], 1 ms. score ([6] p.); 35 cm. + 6 ms. parts; 35 cm. (Box 2, Item 40)
    Holograph in ink and pencil. Score and parts include text in German and English on typewritten inserts. Two slightly different copies of tenor part included; one copy with caption title: Music for tenor voice, 2 violins, viola + cello, poem by Eichendorff; other copy with caption title: Music for tenor voice and strings on insert over original title, Quintet for tenor voice, 2 Vlns, Vla, Cello. Score and one copy of tenor part contain revisions in ink applied directly to manuscript and on pasted inserts. Loose inserts from score and parts enclosed in envelope.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Music, tenor, string quartet. English & German Music for tenor voice and strings / based on a poem by Eichendorff; [music by Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1890 and 1954], 5 ms. parts; 31 cm. (Box 2, Item 41)
    Holograph in ink and pencil. Title from caption of 1st violin part. "Quintet for Tenor Voice, 2 vlns, vla, + Cello (Verses by Eichendorff)"--Cover, tenor part. "Thy image"--Tenor part caption title. Tenor part contains revisions in pencil, red pencil and ink applied directly to manuscipt and on a pasted insert. First violin part marked with a cut and includes text in German and English typewritten on pasted inserts.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Navarro's danse espagnole / Fred'k Slee. [1895], 1 ms. score ([10] p.); 27 x 35 cm. (Box 2, Item 42)
    Holograph in pencil and red ink. For flute, oboe, clarinet, bassoon, 2 cornets, trombone, horn, castanets (or bones), 2 violins, viola, and bass. Caption title. Separated into three sheets. Contains a cut and revisions.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Pienso en ti Two Spanish dances by Navarro: (B) "Pienso en ti" / arranged by Frederick Slee. [1895], 1 ms. score ([4] p.); 18 x 35 cm. (Box 2, Item 43)
    Holograph (Pencil). For flute, oboe, clarinet, bassoon, horn, 2 violins, viola, cello and bass. Caption title. Score incomplete. Originally included in folder containing Navarro's danse espagnole.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Navarro's danse espagnole Navaro's [i.e. Navarro's] danse espagnole / Slee. [1895], 1 ms. score ([2] p.); 27 x 35 cm. (Box 2, Item 44)
    Holograph in ink and pencil. For flute, clarinet, cornet, trombone, percussion, 2 violins, viola, cello and bass. Caption title. Score incomplete. Separated into two sheets. Contains revisions.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Navarro's danse espagnole / Slee. [1895], 9 ms. parts; 18-36 cm. (Box 2, Item 45)
    Holograph in ink and pencil, except viola part: Ms. (Ink) with pencil emendations by the composer. For flute, oboe, horn, 2 violins, viola, and violoncello. Caption title. Includes one additional copy of 1st and 2nd violin parts. All parts contain revisions applied directly to manuscript; oboe part also contains revisions on pasted inserts. Verso of one copy of 1st violin part contains sketches.
  - Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937 Chants populaire.Chanson franc¸aise; arr. The night light: Limousin folk-song / harmonised by Ravel; adapted by Cal de Cott. [between 1910 and 1954], 1 ms. score ([2] p.); 31 cm. + 1 ms. vocal part (1 leaf); 23 cm. (Box 2, Item 46)
    Holograph (Ink). Caption title. Text by Robert Frost. Cover contains words of the song typewritten as text on a pasted insert.
  - Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937 Chants populaires.Chanson franc¸aise; arr. The night light: Limousin folk-song / harmonised by Ravel; adapted by Cal de Cott. [between 1910 and 1954], 1 ms. score (1 leaf); 31 cm. (Box 2, Item 47)
    Holograph in ink and pencil. Caption title. Text by Robert Frost. Contains a revision and words of the song typewritten as text on pasted inserts.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Pastoral / [text by] Franc¸ois Coppe´e; [music by Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [betweeen 1890 and 1954], 1 ms. score ([2] p.); 30 cm. (Box 2, Item 48)
    Holograph (Ink). Cover title. "To Chaminade"--Cover, one photostatic copy. Cover of all copies of score contain words of song typewritten as text on a pasted insert. All copies of score contain revisions on pasted manuscript inserts. "Ritournelle"--Title visible on cover beneath the pasted insert with song text; Ritournelle is the title of the song by Chaminade based on the same text. Two photostatic copies of score inserted.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Pastoral Ritournelle / [text by Franc¸ois Coppe´e; music by Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [betweeen 1890 and 1954], 1 ms. score ([2] p.); 26 cm. (Box 2, Item 49)
    Caption title. Work later revised and title changed to "Pastoral".
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Phantoms / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1890 and 1954], 1 ms. score ([2] p.); 31 cm. (Box 2, Item 50)
    Holograph in ink and pencil. Song for voice and piano. Caption title. Author of text unknown. Two photostatic copies of score inserted.